João Araújo

② Porto, Portugal
(+351) 933 054 687
✓ joaoaraujo2001@hotmail.com

linkedin.com/in/joaoaraujo17

o github.com/Jony-17

SUMMARY _

23 years old graduated in Computer Engineering with particular interest in the area of web development. I'm very interested in everything inherent to creativity, always with the ambition of thriving in the Front-end area. However, the same applies to Full-stack, as I am open to opportunities, always with the aim of constantly growing and learning. <u>Personal website link.</u>

SKILLS _

Front-end: HTML, CSS, SASS, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, JavaScript, React.js

Back-end: PHP, Python

Databases: MySQL, SQL Server

Testing Tools: Jest, React Testing Library **Programming Languages:** Java, C#

Tools: GitHub, Git

Design: Figma, Adobe Illustrator **Methodologies:** Scrum, Kanban

Languages: Portuguese (native), English (B2), Spanish (A1)

Certifications: The Ultimate React Course (2024, by Udemy, in progress), Complete JavaScript Course (2024, by Udemy),

Responsive Web Design (2023, by freeCodeCamp)

EDUCATION _____

Instituto Superior Politécnico Gaya

2021 - 2024

Graduation in Computer Engineering

Instituto Superior Politécnico Gaya

2019 - 2021

CTeSP in Information Systems Technologies and Programming

EXPERIENCE _

WideSkills - Instituto Superior Politécnico Gaya

february 2024 - july 2024

Internal Intership - Mental Health Portal

- I developed a website in the area of mental health as a final course project, with the aim of promoting awareness among university students about the importance of mental health and combating misinformation on the topic.
- I designed and implemented interactive and educational content to tackle and mitigate the lack of knowledge about issues related to mental health.
- This project resulted in the opportunity to write a scientific article, documenting the results and implications of the work carried out.
- Technologies used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, Python.

WeCreateYou

march 2021 - august 2021

Curricular Intership

• I worked mainly with image editing, using Adobe Illustrator, with the aim of improving my user experience skills.

PROJECTS _

CountriesApp | React, Vite, Tailwind CSS, Axios

- Development of an application that allow seeking specific informations of countries and continents.
- Integrated the REST Countries API to fetch comprehensive data, such as population, capitals, currencies and more.

PopCornFilms | React, CRA, CSS, Fetch API

- Development of an application that allow to discover, search for, and rate movies.
- Integrated the OMDb API to retrieve detailed film information, actors and more.

Porfolio | React, CRA, SASS

 Creation of a personal portfolio showcasing personal identity, professional journey, technology stack, obtained certificates, and completed projects